So the question here is, what do you
need to know to really get started with Vue?
And so earlier, we talked about some prerequisites
for the workshop, but this is where I kind of want to start
us as far as ground zero goes.
As long as you have familiarity with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript,
and you have familiarity with the code editor,
that is all you need.
And that might come as a surprise to people,
because a lot of times when we think about frameworks,
we are thinking about it from a build tool perspective.
But we are going to go ahead and show you
how this approach works and why it's actually
a viable approach when it comes to a lot of organizations
looking to either progressively migrate their apps
into a framework.
So here's your Morpheus meme from Matrix.
What if I told you no build tools were needed?
And so again, some of you will be understandably skeptical,
but we're going to actually experience this live ourselves
and go through what this is like.
So with that said, has everyone had a chance
to basically fork the repo, sort of clone it down
to make sure they have that environment ready to go?
OK.
Great.
So the first thing we're going to do,
we talked for a little bit now, let's dive right into some code
and check this out.
So inside of here, you'll notice that there's very little
going on in here.
There's no package.json.
There's no dependencies to run.
It's basically a readme file here,
and we have a couple of HTML files for you
to basically work with.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going
to go ahead and open up my playground HTML
file inside of the browser over here.
And so to make sure everything's working,
I'm just going to go ahead and do an H1 with hello, front end
masters, save, refresh.
There we go.
OK.
Dev environment set up, no build tools required.
Great.
Now, when we think about building your first view app,
I mentioned before, because no build tools are required,
what you can do is you can actually just drop view onto a page.
And so the way we're going to do that
is we're going to go ahead and go onto the view.js.org docs.
And if we go to the guide, I believe it's under quick start,
we'll see.
Here we go.
There's a section here that says using view from the CDN.
And all we're going to do is we're
going to copy this line right here and drop it into our HTML
file.
So all we're going to do here is boom, paste that in.
And so to verify that this worked,
that something actually happened, we're
actually going to go ahead and open up our browser console.
And you'll notice here that, one, it's already alerting us
that we're running a development build of view.
So in other words, if we're going to deploy this,
there's going to need to use a production deployment,
because the size is going to be a bit larger.
But this is fine, because we're learning right now.
So the way you can check that also that this is working
is if you type view, it'll auto-complete.
And you'll notice it'll basically bring up the view object that's
ready for you to do stuff with it.
And so what I'm going to do right now
is I'm going to go ahead and just show you basically
how that kind of works.
So what I'm going to do here is we're going to go ahead
and we're going to create a div.
And just like you typically would expect,
I'm going to call it the div app.
That's all we're going to do.
And then we're going to say, my app in here, save it,
and we refresh.
There you go, my app is showing up here.
And now let's go ahead and actually attach our app.
And how do we do that?
So what we're going to do now is we're
going to open up a script block at the bottom.
And we're actually going to go ahead and bring in a function
from view called create app.
So I'm going to create a constant.
And I'm going to destructure it from view.
So it's going to look like this.
Now, this is an alternative syntax that basically just
calling create app like this, calling the function directly.
But there will be an advantage to this
from a syntax perspective.
So that's why we're destructuring the function out.
And all we're going to do is we're
going to go ahead and say const app equals create app.
And so what that'll do is it'll create a variable called app.
And then it'll go ahead and create set app.
And all we're going to do now is we're going to mount.
Because what we've got to do, we've
got to tell view where it is we want to actually put the app.
So that is where this mount keyword comes in.
And we're going to mount it to the ID of app, which
is using the CSS selector here.
So it'll mount it directly into this part.
So in three lines of codes, we have dropped the view,
or I guess four of you include the CDN.
We've loaded view onto the page.
And we basically created the app.
So if we refresh it, we'll notice nothing's really happening.
And that's totally fine because we haven't
had view display anything yet.
And so when it comes to frameworks,
one of the things that people love about working with frameworks
is that it really helps to track your data across different states.
So that's called reactive data.
So the fact that when something changes,
it'll go ahead and make sure that your HTML page is
updated as expected.
So the way we're going to do this is, inside of our create app,
we're going to pass it an object.
And this object's going to allow us to configure things
about our app.
So think of it as a configuration object.
And what we're going to do is we're
going to pass it a data option.
And what we're going to do is this
is going to be a function that returns an object.
And so we think about what's going on here.
Basically, we're saying, hey, view,
we want you to create an app that's
going to have a data property.
And the reason we're using a function here
is because we want to actually basically maintain
the reactivity in terms of tracking
the latest instance of that object.
Because if you were to do something instead,
like just data like this, the data becomes stale over time.
And there becomes like caching issues.
And so it's being kind of best practice across frameworks
that when you're managing data, you actually
have it be a function that returns an object.
And then the framework will take care of it from there for you.
And so in this, let's go ahead and just add a message here.
And this time, I'll just say, hello, it works.
OK.
So now here, we have our reactive data message.
And the question is, how are we going to actually render
that inside of our app?
Well, the way we're going to do that
is we're going to be using the curly brace syntax.
So this is specific to, well, actually, this
has been a fairly common syntax language.
But as far as the three frameworks are concerned,
this one view uses the double curly brace.
And all we type is message.
That's all it is.
And when we refresh it, you'll notice
your data is now appearing inside of your page,
as you would expect.